<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>StrawPack 2</name>
    <directory>strawpack 2</directory>
    <id>1163138153</id>
    <description>Adds 6 items, 5 trinkets and 1 challenge to the game!

Art and thumbnail by Aczom.
Code by Strawrat.
This mod uses a cropped version of the following sound effect from Freesound: [url=http://freesound.org/people/Robinhood76/sounds/93570/]&quot;01543 flying dragon&quot; by Robinhood76.[/url]

[b][u]NOTE:[/u][/b] If you already have any of these items individually installed, be sure to disable them if you enable this pack to prevent any possible conflicts.

[h1]How to spawn every item and trinket in a room:[/h1]
Execute the following command in the Debug Console: showcase strawpack2

[url=https://www.reddit.com/r/bindingofisaac/comments/6w5kjc/how_can_i_open_the_debug_consol/dm5ib2l/?st=j8heyt7z&amp;sh=7129cd59]How to open the Debug Console.[/url]

[h1]How to get each item/trinket individually:[/h1]

[url=http://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=927173370]Every item/trinket can be found in this collection.[/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/pk9znEt.png[/IMG]
[h1]Fallen Feather (passive - Angel pool):[/h1]

+2 Soul Hearts.

Every time Isaac enters an uncleared room, a feather will fall from the sky.

After it reaches the ground, one of two effects will happen:

1. If the room was cleared while it was falling, every consumable in the room will be doubled (Jera Rune effect). If no consumables exist, a Soul Heart will spawn instead.

2. If it remains uncleared, light beams will be shot down from the sky (Crack the Sky effect).

The time it takes to fall to the ground depends on the number of enemies at the start of the room. This value goes from 6 seconds (when no enemies exist) to 15 seconds (at 16 or more enemies).

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-T5SHxEJycQ]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/TBMW2jd.png[/IMG]
[h1]Lil Spewer (familiar - Treasure pool - REMOVED - now in Booster Pack #5):[/h1]

When picked up, a random pill is dropped on the floor.

Gives Isaac a follower that shoots charged creep shots whose damage and pattern changes depending on Lil Spewer's variant.

Every time Isaac takes a pill, Lil Spewer changes into a different variant.

The pill drop and variant changes are seeded.

Synergizes with BFFS: longer range and the creep line lasts longer.
Synergizes with Lost Cork: larger puddles of creep.

[url=http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1108638164]The list of possible variants can be found here.[/url]

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L2pQfFTfZYo]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/lbB7l0p.png[/IMG]
[h1]Social Circle (trinket):[/h1]

While held, familiars that would normally follow Isaac will now orbit him instead.

This only applies to followers in the familiar chain that follows Isaac. One exception to this is Isaac's Heart, which would always follow Isaac.

Might have no effect on other modded familiars.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v8ihflqp4HY]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/YpsxydB.png[/IMG]
[h1]Familiar Doll (trinket):[/h1]

While held, bosses have a 40% chance to drop items thematically related to them instead of their usual ones.

The trinket can be dropped mid-fight to prevent any items from being replaced.

Mom will [i]always[/i] drop The Polaroid and The Negative first.

Drops from other sources such as Mystery Gift and Eden's Soul while in a Boss Room are also affected.

Synergizes with Mom's Box: chance is 80% instead.

[url=http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1098666521]The list of possible replacements when the trinket effect occurs can be found here.[/url]

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AcwuAJW5t-A]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/dstQlJi.png[/IMG]
[h1]Fly Mod (active familiar - Treasure and Shop pools):[/h1]

Charge: 1 room.

While held, a robotic fly will orbit Isaac, dealing light contact damage and blocking enemy shots.

After activating the item, Fly Mod will leave the orbit and dash for a few seconds, dealing a high amount of damage.

After the fly slows down, it will bounce off the walls for the remainder of the room, dealing a medium amount of damage.

Fly Mod confuses fly enemies that get close to it. It also turns Blue Flies into Locusts if they stay close to it for a few seconds.

Every time Fly Mod kills an enemy, there is 50% for a Blue Fly to spawn.

Synergizes with BFFS: increased area of effect for enemies and Blue Flies + the number of Blue Flies spawned after killing an enemy is increased by the amount of BFFS! items.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0_TKLYxyuI]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/jvX3bb0.png[/IMG]
[h1]Car Key (trinket):[/h1]

While held, if Isaac collides with a locked object with a speed greater than his current maximum possible walking speed, it will be unlocked.

Locked objects include: chests, doors (excluding Mega Satan's Door) and lock blocks*.

* Due to API limitations, these will only be unlocked when you reenter the room.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Sf7soI7DHU]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/2zHi1En.png[/IMG]
[h1]Monstro's Eye (active - Treasure pool):[/h1]

Charge: 6 rooms.

When used, summons Monstro 2 to drop from above, landing on enemies, dealing 120 damage to them and destroying obstacles like rocks.

After dropping down, Monstro 2 will shoot a Brimstone laser with the player's tear effects and damage.

If no enemies are present, Monstro 2 will fall where Isaac is. He won't, however, home towards the player while falling.

While held, there's a 15% chance to shoot concussive tears, causing enemies to walk around randomly.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VtTHq-qB_BQ]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/hYWTpYp.png[/IMG]
[h1]Mom's Mole (passive - Treasure pool):[/h1]

Shot speed up + slight range down.

Isaac's tears now burrow underground at the end of their range. After enough have been burrowed, they'll all reemerge at once with combined tear effects.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JAKo_L46a1E]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/AELHDNg.png[/IMG]
[h1]Mystery Egg (familiar - Treasure pool - REMOVED - now in Booster Pack #5):[/h1]

When Isaac takes damage, Mystery Egg breaks and releases a charmed enemy. The type of enemy spawned depends on how many rooms have been cleared with the familiar (see below).

Spawned monsters have more health than normal.

Synergizes with BFFS!: spawned enemies turn into a random champion type.

[url=http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1016223447]The list of possible charmed enemies can be found here.[/url]

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_crnZEmJu5w]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/N6brqWz.png[/IMG]
[h1]Seed of Discord (trinket):[/h1]

While held, every time Isaac goes down a floor, 3 new special seed effects are added to the run.
When a full batch of 3 seed effects can't be added, a random Challenge effect will be applied.

[b][u]NOTE: some seed effects will disable achievements![/u][/b]

[url=http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=927165094]The list of possible seed and challenge effects can be found here.[/url]

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwNdZ4HdHOY]Demo video![/url]

[IMG]https://i.imgur.com/opeJYLz.png[/IMG]
[h1]Plucked Daisy (trinket):[/h1]

While held, every amount of damage taken has a 50% to either be doubled or ignored.

Synergizes with Mom's Box: same penalty but instead of ignoring the damage, Isaac gets healed for that amount.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7NunFRkgmc]Demo video![/url]

[h1]The Glutton's Fork (challenge):[/h1]

[b]Character:[/b] Isaac
[b]Starting items:[/b] Fallen Feather, PHD, Isaac's Fork and a Gulp! pill.

Every time a room is cleared before the feather hits the ground, every trinket, pill, card and rune held will be dropped on the ground.

Duplicating a trinket with the feather will spawn another random trinket instead.

[b]Conditions:[/b] no Treasure or Dice Rooms.
[b]Goal:[/b] Satan.

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S6T7euV4XVc]Demo video![/url]</description>
    <version>1.3</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
</metadata>
