<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>fallen feather</name>
    <directory>fallen feather</directory>
    <id>1153048172</id>
    <description>[i]&quot;Help from above!&quot;[/i]

Adds a brand new passive item to the Angel Room pool!

Art and The Glutton's Fork idea and design by Aczom.
Code by Strawrat.
This mod uses a cropped version of the following sound effect from Freesound: [url=http://freesound.org/people/Robinhood76/sounds/93570/]&quot;01543 flying dragon&quot; by Robinhood76.[/url]

[h1]Fallen Feather:[/h1]

+2 Soul Hearts.

Every time Isaac enters an uncleared room, a feather will fall from the sky.

After it reaches the ground, one of two effects will happen:

1. If the room was cleared while it was falling, every consumable in the room will be doubled (Jera Rune effect). If no consumables exist, a Soul Heart will spawn instead.

2. If it remains uncleared, light beams will be shot down from the sky (Crack the Sky effect).

The time it takes to fall to the ground depends on the number of enemies at the start of the room. This value goes from 6 seconds (when no enemies exist) to 15 seconds (at 16 or more enemies).

[h1]The Glutton's Fork (challenge):[/h1]

[url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S6T7euV4XVc]See it in action here![/url]

[b]Character:[/b] Isaac

[b]Starting items:[/b] Fallen Feather, PHD, Isaac's Fork and a Gulp! pill.

Every time a room is cleared before the feather hits the ground, every trinket, pill, card and rune held will be dropped on the ground.

Duplicating a trinket with the feather will spawn another random trinket instead.

[b]Conditions:[/b] no Treasure or Dice Rooms.

[b]Goal:[/b] Satan.

[IMG]https://bindingofisaacrebirth.gamepedia.com/media/bindingofisaacrebirth.gamepedia.com/8/86/Isaac%27s_Fork_Icon.png?version=d8236587a6d9921419d74717e8e60f67[/IMG]

This item and challenge will be part of the StrawPack 2 item pack. Stay tuned!</description>
    <version>1.1</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
</metadata>
