<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>seed of discord</name>
    <directory>seed of discord</directory>
    <id>927165094</id>
    <description>[i]&quot;What will your future bring you?&quot;[/i]

Adds a brand new trinket to the game!

While held, every time Isaac goes down a floor, 3 new special seed effects are added to the run.
When a full batch of 3 seed effects can't be added, a random Challenge effect will be applied.

Caution: zany trinket.

[b] [u]NOTE: some seed effects will disable achievements! [/u] [/b]

Includes the following Challenge effects:

Onan's Streak
Aprils Fool
Speed! (without the overtime damage penalty)
Cursed! (for the Cathedral and Sheol only)
Ultra Hard (for the Chest and Dark Room only)

Includes the following Special Seed effects (eggs):

KEEP AWAY - Pickups mimic Isaac's movements.
G0NE S00N - Pickups time out.
FREE 2PAY - Items and consumables cost money.
C0ME BACK - Enemies, including bosses, respawn once Isaac leaves the room.
BRWN SNKE - Isaac leaves a trail of poop behind him as he walks.
DARK NESS - Permanent Curse of Darkness.
N1TE L1TE - Provides immunity to Curse of Darkness.
BRAV ERY - Isaac fires tears in the same direction that he moves. Removes the normal ability to fire tears.
C0WR D1CE - Isaac fires tears in the opposite direction that he moves. Removes the normal ability to fire tears.
AX1S ALGN - Isaac cannot move diagonally.
CAM0 K1DD - Isaac blends into the ground.
CAM0 DR0P - Pickups and items blend into the ground.
KAPP A - Isaac turns gray.
PTCH BLCK - Isaac and his tears turn completely black.
TEAR GL0W - Isaac's tears glow.
BL00 00DY - Makes a lot more blood appear after enemies die.
B00B T00B - Applies a filter that makes the game look like it's being played through a cathode ray tube.
DYSL EX1A - All in-game text is rearranged.
MED1 C1NE - All pill names and descriptions show ???.
FACE D0WN - All card names and descriptions show ???.
CHAM P10N - All enemies turn into champions if possible.
FRA1 DN0T - Every few seconds, all enemies become scared.
FART SNDS - All sound effects are replaced with farts.
SL0W 4ME2 - Music speed is affected by Isaac's walking speed.
HART BEAT - The lower Isaac's health is, the slower the music is.
ANDA NTE - Music is slowed down.
LARG HETO - Music is significantly slowed down.
ALLE GR0 - Music is sped up.
PRES T0 - Music is significantly sped up.

This trinket will be part of the StrawPack 2 item pack. Stay tuned!

Art by Aczom and code by Strawrat.</description>
    <version>1.2</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
</metadata>
