<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>lil spewer</name>
    <directory>lil spewer</directory>
    <id>1108638164</id>
    <description>[i]&quot;Puking buddy!&quot;[/i]

 [url=https://vignette2.wikia.nocookie.net/kongregate/images/f/f7/Spewer.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20110828154448][IMG]http://i.imgur.com/nJlLTc1.png[/IMG][/url]

Adds a brand new chargeable familiar to the Treasure Room pool!

When picked up, a random pill is dropped on the floor.

Gives Isaac a follower that shoots charged creep shots whose damage and pattern changes depending on Lil Spewer's variant.

Every time Isaac takes a pill, Lil Spewer changes into a different variant.

The pill drop and variant changes are seeded.

Synergizes with BFFS: longer range and the creep line lasts longer.

Synergizes with Lost Cork: larger puddles of creep.

[h1]All 5 Possible Lil Spewer Variants:[/h1]

[IMG]http://i.imgur.com/HfG1NMt.png[/IMG]
[b]Normal:[/b]
Shoots a medium-range line of green medium damage creep.
Always the first variant when the item is picked up.
Can be used as a general purpose attacking familiar.

[IMG]http://i.imgur.com/05eyLFX.png[/IMG]
[b]Black:[/b]
Shoots a long-range line of black slowing creep.
The line has a longer lifespan than the previous variant.
Can be used as a general purpose defending familiar.

[IMG]http://i.imgur.com/9C3HJnf.png[/IMG]
[b]Red:[/b]
Shoots a fast long-range line of red high damage creep.
These puddles have a very short lifespan.
A larger puddle of red creep with a longer lifespan is spawned at the end of its range.
Can be used to deal a killing blow to several lined up enemies.

[IMG]http://i.imgur.com/jumA23D.png[/IMG]
[b]Yellow:[/b]
Shoots a short-range line of yellow creep whose size and damage increases with range.
The last puddle of creep in the line can potentially deal more damage than any other Lil Spewer variant (capped at 20).
Can be used for close-range crowd control.

[IMG]http://i.imgur.com/9dlc7gw.png[/IMG]
[b]White:[/b]
Shoots two arching lines of white slowing creep that form a circle.
The lines have the longest lifespan of any variant.
Can be used to trap enemies in a circle while Isaac makes his escape.

This familiar will be part of StrawPack 2. Stay tuned!

Art by Aczom and code by Strawrat.
Special thanks to [url=https://www.youtube.com/user/Lytebringr/]Lytebringr[/url] for his modding tutorials.

Based on the flash game [url=http://www.kongregate.com/games/2darray/spewer]Spewer[/url] made by Edmund McMillen and Eli Piilonen. The original flash game is also available in [url=http://store.steampowered.com/app/214790/The_Basement_Collection/]The Basement Collection[/url].</description>
    <version>1.2</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
</metadata>
